Akshay CA Data Scientist, IBM Certified

Life Republic, Marunji, Pune - 411057 | 9731227136 | akshay.ca42@gmail.com

Career Objective

Looking for a position in Data Science, where I can apply my skills and experience to support the project growth and success. Looking for an opportunity to improve my skills and add values.

About me

Software Engineer with 2.3 years of experience at LTI (Larsen & Toubro InfoTech). Data Science and ML/AI enthusiast. Experienced at creating deep neural networks and ML models, using predictive data modeling, analyzing, processing and mining data to deliver insights and implement action-oriented solutions to business problems.

Skills & Abilities

- Expertise in **Data** Cleaning, Analysis, Mining and Visualization, Feature Engineering, **Machine Learning** Algorithms, **Neural Networks and Deep Learning**.
- Improving ML / Deep Neural Networks Models: Hyperparameter tuning, Regularization, Model Validation and Optimization.
- Structuring Machine Learning Projects,
- Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs), Sequence
 Models RNNs, Natural Language Processing (NLP).
- Feature Engineering.
- Object-Oriented Programming, Quality Analysis, UI Automation Testing frameworks, Knowledge of Insurance domain, Critical thinking and Good communication skills.

Programming languages and Tools

Python – NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, SciPy, Scikit-learn, TensorFlow and Keras, **Jupyter**, PyCharm, **GIT**,

MySQL, **Selenium**, **Cucumber**- BDD, **Jenkins**, **DevOps**, **C#**, Visual Studio, Microsoft TFS and Office products,

Familiar with **Apache Spark**, **Hadoop** big data tool and **Tableau**, **R Studio** and **MongoDB**.

Projects

- My Data science projects
- Machine Learning Projects
- Convolutional Neural Networks
- Sequence Model RNNs, Natural Language
 Processing

Experience

Automation Test Engineer, BB&T- Bank holding company

June 2018 – Present

BB&T acts as a third-party agent that assists in selling of insurance policies of various insurance companies in return for a percentage in form of commission.

- Sole ownership of Automation in two complex projects.
- Introduced Behavior Driven Development (BDD),
 Cucumber and developed testing frameworks.
 Used SpecFlow with Selenium and C# for Direct Billing
 System and for Carrier Payable System using Page Object Model (POM) design pattern.
- Followed pure SCRUM Agile methodology.
- Efficiently performed testing for biweekly releases pertaining to enhancements, change requests and defects.
- Used Microsoft Azure TFS (Team Foundation Server) for reporting, requirements management, project management, automated builds and release management capabilities. GIT for source code management.

Automation Test Engineer, Pro-liability.com

Nov 2017 - May 2018

Administered by Mercer Consumer, offers Professional Liability Insurance tailored mainly to Health-Care professional.

 Helped in developing and maintaining the Hybrid testing framework which was developed using Maven, Selenium with JAVA, TestNG, Sauce Labs, Extent reports and Jenkins.

> Akshay CA Data Scientist, IBM Certified

Certifications IBM Data Science Professional Certificate

Deep Learning Specialization offered by deeplearning.io

Machine Learning with Python

Data Analysis with Python

Data Visualization with Python

ISTQB - International Software Testing Qualifications Board

CP-SAT - Certified Professional – Selenium Automation Testing

Education Information Science Engineering

2013-2017

PES Institute of Technology – Bangalore

• Was part of College Basketball Team.

• Active member of Maaya- Creative Department Team.

Hobbies and Interests

Basketball, Sketching, Reading, Artificial Intelligence

and **Data Science**

Contact Me <u>GitHub - Personal portfolio</u>,

<u>LinkedIn</u>